<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>fsharp on type-nat</title>
    <link>http://type-nat.ch/categories/fsharp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in fsharp on type-nat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://type-nat.ch/categories/fsharp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FsCheck and co: Testing Excel Financial Functions</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/fscheck-testing-excel-financial-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/fscheck-testing-excel-financial-functions/</guid>
      <description>Excel Financial Functions library is a .NET library written by Luca Bolognese that provides the full set of financial functions from Excel. It can be used from both F# and C# as well as from other .NET languages. The main goal for the library is compatibility with Excel, by providing the same functions, with the same behaviour.
 The library was recently moved to GitHub and its new home is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Log(music) with Undertone</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/log-music-with-undertone/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/log-music-with-undertone/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a physicist, biologist, economist, data scientist, whatever, the chances are you&amp;rsquo;ll meet the Markov chains sooner or later. And today we&amp;rsquo;ll try them on&amp;hellip; music!
If you&amp;rsquo;re not up to the math part, feel free to skip it.
Math The system states changes are represented with a help of transition matrix, describing the probabilities of possible transitions. This matrix is a key to determine the state of the model after n steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying out Deedle with Bones and Regression</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/trying-out-deedle-with-bones-and-regression/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/trying-out-deedle-with-bones-and-regression/</guid>
      <description>I usually don&amp;rsquo;t need to run a regression anywhere, but it&amp;rsquo;s kind of chasing me recently, starting with the Asset Pricing class and several variations of returns regressions (signed up to look at the familiar things from a different point of view&amp;hellip; well, I definitely succeeded: have you ever thought about drawing the returns, prices and discount factors in space, all at once? 1. But I &amp;lsquo;cheated&amp;rsquo; and completed the assignments with R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[F#] Dev Life&#39;s Little Pleasures</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/f-dev-lifes-little-pleasures/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/f-dev-lifes-little-pleasures/</guid>
      <description>Different languages have some little things that make the life easier: for devs, their QAs and customers. The app is fast and behaves correctly, the code looks simple and understandable - everyone is happy.
Here are the slides and a couple of code samples from my talk &amp;ldquo;[F#] Dev Life&amp;rsquo;s Little Pleasures&amp;rdquo;. Briefly, it takes some real-world problems 1 and provides the simple solutions.
 Units of Measure - need to admit, I was a long time sceptic (c&amp;rsquo;mon, how can you get kg and m^2 mixed up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel-DNA: Three Stories</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/excel-dna-three-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/excel-dna-three-stories/</guid>
      <description>Intro: Simulation A couple of days ago I found a spreadsheet, potentially quite an interesting one. In theory, it should run a simple simulation (50000 paths by default) written in VBA - I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s several minutes of work in the worst case. However, it took slightly more. One working day, to be precise. I still have no idea what it tried to do, why it ate 97% of CPU and even what exactly it computed, because all that ended with a weird error and crashed Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>