<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Excel on type-nat</title>
    <link>http://type-nat.ch/tags/excel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Excel on type-nat</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://type-nat.ch/tags/excel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>FsCheck and co: Testing Excel Financial Functions</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/fscheck-testing-excel-financial-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/fscheck-testing-excel-financial-functions/</guid>
      <description>Excel Financial Functions library is a .NET library written by Luca Bolognese that provides the full set of financial functions from Excel. It can be used from both F# and C# as well as from other .NET languages. The main goal for the library is compatibility with Excel, by providing the same functions, with the same behaviour.
 The library was recently moved to GitHub and its new home is here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Excel-DNA: Three Stories</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/excel-dna-three-stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/excel-dna-three-stories/</guid>
      <description>Intro: Simulation A couple of days ago I found a spreadsheet, potentially quite an interesting one. In theory, it should run a simple simulation (50000 paths by default) written in VBA - I&amp;rsquo;d say it&amp;rsquo;s several minutes of work in the worst case. However, it took slightly more. One working day, to be precise. I still have no idea what it tried to do, why it ate 97% of CPU and even what exactly it computed, because all that ended with a weird error and crashed Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days and Ghost Refinements</title>
      <link>http://type-nat.ch/post/days-and-ghost-refinements/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://type-nat.ch/post/days-and-ghost-refinements/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s look at the simple function, which calculates the number of days between dates, when there&amp;rsquo;re 30 days in a month (and 360 in a year).
Something like this F# code:
1 2  let days360 sy sm sd ey em ed = (ey - sy) * 360 + (em - sm) * 30 + (ed - sd)   We can even write a bunch of tests to be sure the function works:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>